# 大家好 今天去兄弟家的瓜地裡面看一下 (註︰英文沒有「瓜」這個概念，所以寫成菜地算了)
Hi everyone! Today we're gonna have a look at our buddy's veggie farm.
# 你看 這裡 他家的 他家的那個攀蒲開了好多花呀
Look! Here! His, the "panpu" (pumpkin) at his place are now blooming.
# 摘那個花回去
Let's pick some those flowers back.
# 你看
Look!
# 這個就是母花 有果的這個母花
This is female. Those with fruits are female.
# 這個公的就是 沒果子的
And this is male. It has, like, no fruits.
# 這就是
It's ah,
# 公的
it's male.
# 把它摘的就摘這個
That's exactly what we wanna pick now.
# 你看 這固就是傳播花粉的
Look! They're for spreading the pollen.
# 這花粉在這裡
The pollen is here.
# 我們主要就要這個
In fact, that's what we need.
# 裹上面粉 用油炸一下
I'll coat it with flour, and then fry it.
# 很好吃的哦 這個
It's really tasty, you know.
# 摘了一朵
So now I have one.
# 這還有一棵
Here's another one.
# 用刀來 把它割回去
Let me cut it off, with a knife.
# 這裡也有一棵
And here's another one.
# 這公花 不摘掉也會浪費的
The male flowers, would become a waste even if they're left here.
# 太多公的了 不用那麼多的
They're are simply too many male. We don't need that many.
# 去搞幾個母的就行啦 (註︰這句應該是不完整的，所以不太明白)
With a few female, that's it!
# 這些都是沒用的
These are all useless.
# 留在這裡
Their sole purpose here,
# 只能用來傳播花粉
is spreading pollen.
# 這公的要一個就夠啦 傳播花粉
One single male is everything that's needed. It spreads the pollen,
# 兩個就把它傳 傳 傳過去啦
it spreads, spreads, spreads in no time.
# 你看 這還有一個黃色的哦 這個誰噠 這個
Look! Here's also a yellow one. Whose is it, this one?
# 順便摘一個回去
Why not take one with me?
# 兄弟家的
It's my buddy's.
# 昨天我還跟他說過了
I talked with him yesterday.
# 說 摘一個攀蒲給我
I've asked him, to give me a "panpu".
# 現在要摘花啦
I'm gonna pick the flowers now.
# 長了很多南瓜哦 這裡有個大南瓜
Here are a lot of pumpkins. And here's a big pumpkin.
# 你看 這一朵它還
Look! This flower is still,
# 藏在這裡
hiding here.
# 直接就把你擰下來
I twist you off right away.
# 管你願不願意
You like it or not, I don't care.
# 有點毛 回去洗一下就好了
It's a bit furry. I'll wash it.
# 嗯
Um!
# 有點香
It smells quite good.
# 你看 兄弟家這裡還種了茄子哦
Look! My buddy also has eggplants here.
# 這茄子都已經超大了
The eggplants are already oversized.
# 他都不摘
But he didn't pick them.
# 我幫它
Let me help him.
# 你看 它茄子了這個 不知道還能不能吃
Look! It's an old eggplant. I wonder if it's still edible.
# 摘 摘 摘幾個回去
Let me pick, pick, pick some back home.
# 不要摘那麼多 這個 摘去 不知道好不好吃
I'm not picking too many. I'll, take them with me. But I wonder if they taste good.
# 你看 來一趟 是不是
Look! A trip here, isn't it,
# 收獲滿滿的
fruitful?
# 還有沒有其它的
Is there anything else?
# 西瓜他又不種 種西瓜多好啊
He doesn't grow any watermelons. Watermelons would be wonderful.
# 又可以吃上幾天了
These can feed me in the next few days.
# 下次再來
Let's come again next time.
# 現在回來啦 天氣 太熱啦 它這
So now we're back. It's ah, it's too hot now.
# 把這心挖出來
We scratch out the heart,
# 把它的心挖出來
scratch out its heart.
# 然後再把它撕開
And then we spread it open.
# 這樣就容易洗一點
So that I can wash it more easily.
# 不然會有小蟲子藏在裡面的
Otherwise, some small bugs might be hiding inside.
# 鮮黃色的
Golden yellow.
# 這個壞的 臭的
This one is rotten, and stinky.
# 壞的就攝影小哥摘的
The rotten ones are all picked by Mr. Cameraman.
# 你看一條蟲 跟我搶吃的
Look! A bug! Aya, you wanna take the food away from me?
# 把它洗一下
Let me wash it.
# 好多花粉
There's a lot of pollen.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 拿面粉來 裹上面
Take some flour. Coat it with flo..
# 面粉 然後用油炸一下
with the flour. And then fry it.
# 把它撕成一小塊一小塊
Tear it up into small pieces.
# 太大塊了一下那個
They would cling together if, I mean,
# 粘在一起
they're in big pieces.
# 這個撕成小塊是 最好的
So, tearing them up into small pieces, is the best way.
# 好香啊
It smells so good!
# 多放點鹽 進到這
Put some salt, into the bowl.
# 摘一下這個 要不然沒甚味道 (註︰他重覆了一次「要不然」但原字幕沒出現，我翻譯跟著重覆了)
Yea, put some... It would, it would be tasteless otherwise.
# 鹽怎麼不出來
Why isn't the salt coming out?
# 可以
Alright!
# 嗯 拌均勻啦 把這個面粉
Um! It's well stirred now. The flour,
# 搞一點去
put some here.
# 這是我們這邊的蕉芋粉 不是面粉哦
It's in fact the Indian shot starch here, not really flour.
# 加點這個辣椒粉
Put some chilli powder.
# 搞多一點 (註︰沒有原字幕)
More!
# 要不然 沒甚麼味道
Otherwise, it wouldn't taste anything.
# 最近的口味越來越重啦
I'm craving for stronger and stronger tastes recently.
# 點吃辣椒就沒那重的口味 (註︰不太明白)
Some chilli can reduce a lot of other flavourings.
# 好啦 搞過去 用油炸一下 就可以出鍋啦
Alright! We take it over there, and fry it. Then that's it.
# 放顆蛋去 更香一點
Put an egg. The aroma would be more significant.
# 這樣好看哦
It looks really nice.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 它的顏色看起來好鮮豔哦
The colour is so bright and attractive.
# 看上去就好吃
It looks really tasty.
# 可以啦 一會就好了
Alright! It doesn't take long.
# 看上去就好吃
It looks really tasty,
# 像個燒餅一樣 (註︰不想太多注釋甚麼是燒餅，這不是重點，反正就是金黃色煎炸扁平狀的食品吧)
just like a pancake.
# 很靚哦
Beautiful!
# 太燙啦 等一下來吃
It's too hot! I'll enjoy it in a while.
# 你看 這個油炸好啦
Look! So I've fried them.
# 看上去就很有食欲
It looks really appetising.
# 金黃金黃的
Golden yellow
# 嗯
Um~
# 很不錯哦 好香啊
It's really not bad. It smells so good!
# 你看 香味把小狗都吹過來啦
Look! The smell is bringing the doggies here.
# 這是素食 沒肉的
It's veggie. There's no meat.
# 你不要的
You don't like it.
# 這個不知道甚味道 沒吃過
It's ah... How should I describe the taste? It's new to me.
# 吃起來就是
It's like,
# 很香
it smells good.
# 嗯 雞蛋味
Um! There's the taste of eggs,
# 也有攀蒲花的味
and of pumpkin flowers as well,
# 還有油味
and of oil too.
# 給一塊給你吃 看你要不要
I give you one. See if you like it.
# 好不好吃
Does it taste good?
# 可以哦 這小狗會吃哦
Not bad. This doggy eats it.
# 嗯 那條就不吃
Um! That one is not eating.
# 那條狗不是好狗
That dog is not a good dog.
# 你也不吃
You don't like it neither.
# 就小黑吃 來
Nobody likes it but Blacky. C'mon!
# 小黑 來
Blacky, c'mon!
# 它會接的哦 這狗
She can catch the food, this dog, you know.
# 還想不想吃
You want more?
# 小黑懷孕了
Blacky is pregnant.
# 肚子那麼大
Her belly is so big now.
# 好啦 今天的視頻到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 準備吃午飯了
It's lunch time now.